In the next few videos I'd
在接下来的视频中
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
like to talk about machine learning system design.
我将谈到机器学习系统的设计
These videos will touch on
这些视频将谈及
the main issues that you may
在设计复杂的机器学习系统时
face when designing a
你将遇到的
complex machine learning system,
主要问题
and will actually try to give
同时我们会试着
advice on how to
给出一些关于
strategize putting together a complex machine learning system.
如何巧妙构建一个复杂的机器学习系统的建议
In case this next set
接下来的视频
of videos seems a little
可能看起来
disjointed that's because these
有点不连贯
videos will touch on a
因为这些视频会涉及
range of the different issues that
一些你在设计机器学习系统时
you may come across when designing complex learning systems.
可能会遇到的不同问题
And even though the
虽然
next set of videos may seem
下面的课程的
somewhat less mathematical, I think
的数学性可能不是那么强
that this material may turn
但是我认为我们将要讲到的这些东西
out to be very useful, and
是非常有用的
potentially huge time savers
可能在构建大型的机器学习系统时
when you're building big machine learning systems.
节省大量的时间
Concretely, I'd like to
具体的说
begin with the issue of
我首先要讲的是
prioritizing how to spend
当我们在进行机器学习时
your time on what to work
着重要考虑什么问题
on, and I'll begin
首先我要举一个
with an example on spam classification.
垃圾邮件分类的例子
Let's say you want to build a spam classifier.
假如你想建立一个垃圾邮件分类器
Here are a couple of examples
看这些垃圾邮件与
of obvious spam and non-spam emails.
非垃圾邮件的例子
if the one on the left tried to sell things.
左边这封邮件想向你推销东西
And notice how spammers
注意 这封垃圾邮件
will deliberately misspell words,
有意的拼错一些单词 就像
like Vincent with a 1 there, and mortgages.
"Med1cine" 中有一个1 "m0rtgage"里有个0
And on the right as maybe
右边的邮件
an obvious example of non-stamp
显然不是一个垃圾邮件
email, actually email from my younger brother.
实际上这是我弟弟写给我的
Let's say we have a labeled
假设我们已经有一些
training set of some
加过标签的训练集
number of spam emails and
包括标注的垃圾邮件
some non-spam emails denoted
表示为y=1
with labels y equals 1 or 0,
和非垃圾邮件 表示为y=0
how do we build a
我们如何
classifier using supervised learning
以监督学习的方法来构造一个分类器
to distinguish between spam and non-spam?
来区分垃圾邮件和非垃圾邮件呢？
In order to apply supervised learning,
为了应用监督学习
the first decision we must
我们首先
make is how do
必须确定的是
we want to represent x, that
如何用邮件的特征
is the features of the email.
构造向量x
Given the features x and
给出训练集中的
the labels y in our
特征x和标签y
training set, we can then
我们就能够训练出某种分类器
train a classifier, for example using logistic regression.
比如用逻辑回归的方法
Here's one way to choose
这里有一种选择
a set of features for our emails.
邮件的一些特征变量的方法
We could come up with,
比如说我们可能会想出
say, a list of maybe
一系列单词
a hundred words that we think
或者成百上千的单词
are indicative of whether e-mail
我们可以认为这些单词
is spam or non-spam, for
能够用来区分垃圾邮件或非垃圾邮件
example, if a piece of
比如说 如果有封邮件
e-mail contains the word 'deal'
包含单词"deal(交易)"
maybe it's more likely to be
那么它就很有可能是一封垃圾邮件
spam if it contains
同时
the word  'buy' maybe more
包含单词"buy(买)"的邮件
likely to be spam, a
也很有可能是一封垃圾邮件
word like 'discount' is more
包含"discount(折扣)"的邮件
likely to be spam, whereas if
也很有可能是垃圾邮件
a piece of email contains my name,
如果一封邮件中
Andrew, maybe that means
包含了我的名字"Andrew"
the person actually knows who
这有可能是一个知道我的人写的
I am and that might mean it's
这说明这封邮件
less likely to be spam.
不太可能是垃圾邮件
And maybe for some reason I think
因为某些原因 我认为
the word "now" may be
"now(现在)"这个单词表明了
indicative of non-spam because
这封邮件可能并不是垃圾邮件
I get a lot of urgent
因为我经常收到一些很紧急的邮件
emails, and so on,
当然还有别的单词
and maybe we choose a hundred words or so.
我们可以选出这样成百上千的单词
Given a piece of email,
给出一封这样的邮件
we can then take this piece
我们可以将这封邮件
of email and encode
用一个特征向量
it into a feature
来表示
vector as follows.
方法如下
I'm going to take my list of a
现在我列出一些
hundred words and sort
之前选好的单词
them in alphabetical order say.
然后按字典序排序
It doesn't have to be sorted.
其实并不是一定要排序的啦
But, you know, here's a, here's
你看
my list of words, just count
这些是之前的单词 像“discount”
and so on, until eventually
等等
I'll get down to now, and so
还有单词"now" 等等
on and given a piece
看看这个例子
of e-mail like that shown on the
右边的这封邮件
right, I'm going to
我准备
check and see whether or
检查一下这些词汇
not each of these words
看它们是否
appears in the e-mail and then
出现在这封邮件中
I'm going to define a feature
我用一个
vector x where in
特征向量x
this piece of an email on
表示右边的这封邮件
the right, my name doesn't
我的名字没有出现
appear so I'm gonna put a zero there.
因此这里是0
The word "by" does appear,
单词"buy(购买)"出现了
so I'm gonna put a one there
所以这里是1
and I'm just gonna put one's or zeroes.
注意在向量里面只有1或0 表示有没有出现
I'm gonna put a
所以尽管"buy"出现了两次
one even though the word "by" occurs twice.
这里仍然只是1
I'm not gonna recount how many times the word occurs.
注意我不会去统计每个词出现的次数
The word "due" appears, I put a one there.
单词"deal"也出现了 所以这里也是1
The word "discount" doesn't appear, at
单词"discount"并没有出现
least not in this this little
至少在这封邮件里是这样
short email, and so on.
以此类推
The word "now" does appear and so on.
单词"now"出现了
So I put ones and zeroes
所以我在特征向量中
in this feature vector depending on
依据对应的单词是否出现
whether or not a particular word appears.
填上0和1
And in this example my
在这个例子中
feature vector would have
因为我选择了100个单词
to mention one hundred,
用于表示是否可能为垃圾邮件
if I have a hundred,
所以
if if I chose a hundred
这个特征向量x
words to use for
的维度是100
this representation and each
并且
of my features Xj will
如果这个特定的单词
basically be 1 if
即单词 j 出现在
you have a particular word that,
这封邮件中
we'll call this word j, appears
那么每一个特征变量
in the email and Xj
Xj 的值为1
would be zero otherwise.
反之 Xj为0
Okay.
好的
So that gives me
这样我们就可以使用特征向量
a feature representation of a piece of email.
来表示这封邮件
By the way, even though I've
顺便说一句
described this process as manually
虽然我所描述的这个过程是我自己
picking a hundred words, in
选取的100个单词
practice what's most commonly
但是在实际工作中 最普遍的做法是
done is to look through
遍历整个训练集
a training set, and in
然后
the training set depict the
在训练集中
most frequently occurring n words
选出出现次数最多的n个单词
where n is usually between ten
n一般介于10,000和50,000之间
thousand and fifty thousand, and use
然后把这些单词
those as your features.
作为你要用的特征
So rather than manually picking a
因此不同于手动选取
hundred words, here you look
我们只用遍历
through the training examples and
训练样本
pick the most frequently occurring words
然后选出出现频率最高的词语
like ten thousand to fifty thousand
差不多是10,000到50,000个单词
words, and those form the
这些单词会构成特征
features that you are going
这样你就可以用它们
to use to represent your email for spam classification.
来做垃圾邮件分类
Now, if you're building a
如果你正在构造一个垃圾邮件分类器
spam classifier one question
你应该会面对这样一个问题
that you may face is, what's
那就是
the best use of your time
如何在有限的时间和精力下
in order to make your
改进你的方法
spam classifier have higher accuracy, you have lower error.
从而使得你的垃圾邮件分类器具有较高的准确度
One natural inclination is going to collect lots of data.
从直觉上讲 是要收集大量的数据
Right?
对吧？
And in fact there's this tendency
事实上确实好多人这么做
to think that, well the
很多人认为
more data we have the better the algorithm will do.
收集越多的数据 算法就会表现的越好
And in fact, in the email
事实上
spam domain, there are actually
就垃圾邮件分类而言
pretty serious projects called Honey
有一个叫做"Honey Pot"的项目
Pot Projects, which create fake
它可以建立一个
email addresses and try to
假的邮箱地址
get these fake email addresses into
故意将这些地址
the hands of spammers and use
泄露给发垃圾邮件的人
that to try to collect tons
这样就能收到大量的垃圾邮件
of spam email, and therefore
你看 这样的话
you know, get a lot of spam data to train learning algorithms.
我们就能得到非常多的垃圾邮件来训练学习算法
But we've already seen in the
但是
previous sets of videos
在前面的课程中我们知道
that getting lots of data will often help, but not all the time.
大量的数据可能会有帮助 也可能没有
But for most machine learning problems,
对于大部分的机器学习问题
there are a lot of other things
还有很多办法
you could usually imagine doing to improve performance.
用来提升机器学习的效果
For spam, one thing you
比如对于垃圾邮件而言
might think of is to develop
也许你会想到
more sophisticated features on the
用更复杂的特征变量
email, maybe based on the email routing information.
像是邮件的路径信息
And this would be information contained in the email header.
这种信息通常会出现在邮件的标题中
So, when spammers send email,
因此 垃圾邮件发送方在发送垃圾邮件时
very often they will try
他们总会试图
to obscure the origins of
让这个邮件的来源变得模糊一些
the email, and maybe
或者是
use fake email headers.
用假的邮件标题
Or send email through very
或者通过不常见的服务器
unusual sets of computer service.
来发送邮件
Through very unusual routes, in order to get the spam to you.
用不常见的路由 他们就能给你发送垃圾邮件
And some of this information will be reflected in the email header.
而且这些信息也有可能包含在邮件标题部分
And so one can imagine,
因此可以想到
looking at the email headers and
我们可以通过邮件的标题部分
trying to develop more sophisticated features
来构造更加复杂的特征
to capture this sort of
来获得一系列的邮件路由信息
email routing information to identify if something is spam.
进而判定这是否是一封垃圾邮件
Something else you might consider doing
你还可能会想到别的方法
is to look at the
比如
email message body, that is
从邮件的正文出发
the email text, and try to develop more sophisticated features.
寻找一些复杂点的特征
For example, should the word
例如
'discount' and the word
单词"discount"
'discounts' be treated as
是否和单词"discounts"是一样的
the same words or should
又比如
we have treat the words 'deal' and 'dealer' as the same word?
单词"deal(交易)"和"dealer(交易商)"是否也应视为等同
Maybe even though one is
甚至 像这个例子中
lower case and one in capitalized in this example.
有的单词小写有的大写
Or do we want more complex features about punctuation because maybe spam
或者我们是否应该用标点符号来构造复杂的特征变量
is using exclamation marks a lot more.
因为垃圾邮件可能会更多的使用感叹号
I don't know.
这些都不一定
And along the same lines, maybe
同样的
we also want to develop more
我们也可能构造
sophisticated algorithms to detect
更加复杂的算法来检测
and maybe to correct to deliberate misspellings,
或者纠正那些故意的拼写错误
like mortgage, medicine, watches.
例如 "m0rtgage" "med1cine" "w4tches"
Because spammers actually do this,
因为垃圾邮件发送方确实这么做了
because if you have watches
因为如果你将4放到"w4tches"中
with a 4 in there then well,
那么
with the simple technique that we
用我们之前提到的
talked about just now, the spam
简单的方法
classifier might not equate
垃圾邮件分类器不会把"w4tches"
this as the same thing as the
和"watches"
word "watches," and so it
看成一样的
may have a harder time realizing
这样我们就很难区分这些
that something is spam with these deliberate misspellings.
故意拼错的垃圾邮件
And this is why spammers do it.
发垃圾邮件的也很机智 他们这么做就逃避了一些过滤
While working on a machine learning
当我们使用机器学习时
problem, very often you
总是可以“头脑风暴”一下
can brainstorm lists of different things to try, like these.
想出一堆方法来试试 就像这样
By the way, I've actually
顺带一提
worked on the spam
我有一段时间
problem myself for a while.
研究过垃圾邮件分类的问题
And I actually spent quite some time on it.
实际上我花了很多时间来研究这个
And even though I kind
尽管我能够理解
of understand the spam problem,
垃圾邮件分类的问题
I actually know a bit about it,
我确实懂一些这方面的东西
I would actually have a very
但是
hard time telling you of
我还是很难告诉你
these four options which is
这四种方法中
the best use of your time
你最该去使用哪一种
so what happens, frankly what
事实上 坦白地说
happens far too often is
最常见的情况是
that a research group or
一个研究小组
product group will randomly fixate on one of these options.
可能会随机确定其中的一个方法
And sometimes that turns
但是有时候
out not to be the most
这种方法
fruitful way to spend your
并不是最有成效的
time depending, you know, on which
你知道
of these options someone ends up randomly fixating on.
你只是随机选择了其中的一种方法
By the way, in fact, if
实际上
you even get to the stage
当你需要通过
where you brainstorm a list
头脑风暴来想出
of different options to try, you're
不同方法来尝试去提高精度的时候
probably already ahead of the curve.
你可能已经超越了很多人了
Sadly, what most people do is
令人难过的是 大部分人
instead of trying to list
他们并不尝试着
out the options of things
列出可能的方法
you might try, what far too
他们做的
many people do is wake up
只是
one morning and, for some
某天早上醒来
reason, just, you know, have a weird
因为某些原因
gut feeling that, "Oh let's
有了一个突发奇想
have a huge honeypot project
"让我们来试试 用Honey Pot项目
to go and collect tons more data"
收集大量的数据吧"
and for whatever strange reason just
不管出于什么奇怪的原因
sort of wake up one morning and randomly
早上的灵机一动
fixate on one thing and just
还是随机选一个
work on that for six months.
然后干上大半年
But I think we can do better.
但是我觉得我们有更好的方法
And in particular what I'd
是的
like to do in the next
我们将在随后的课程中
video is tell you about
讲到这个
the concept of error analysis
那就是误差分析
and talk about the way
我会告诉你
where you can try
怎样用一个
to have a more systematic way
更加系统性的方法
to choose amongst the options
从一堆不同的方法中
of the many different things you
选取合适的那一个
might work, and therefore be
因此
more likely to select what
你更有可能选择
is actually a good way
一个真正的好方法
to spend your time, you know
能让你花上几天几周 甚至是几个月
for the next few weeks, or next few days or the next few months.
去进行深入的研究